# Shailendra Jain → +91-9967219623 shailendrajain28@gmail.com

in /shailendrajain28 (7) /shailendrajain2892

## Summary

High-energy, confident professional with an infectious enthusiasm for technology, with 8 years of experience in developing robust code in python, C, C++ for high-volume businesses. DevOps Experience in deploying application using Kubernetes and AWS. Dedicated for work and eager to learn new things. Ready to accept new challenges with my sincere hard work and solve business problems.

### **Education**

#### **Jabalpur Engineering College**

2009 - 2013

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology

Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh

**♥** Skills

Programming Languages Python, Machine Learning, C, C++, Kubernetes, AWS, Flask, SQL

**Experience** 

Machine Learning Masters Program from Grey Atom School of Data Science

Jan 2019 - June 2019

JP Morgan Chase

Feb 2020 – Present Mumbai, Maharashtra

Associate, Python Software Engineer, DevOps, ML Data Engineer

- > I am working here as a software engineer. I need to Develop an application to host various Machine Learning Model which needs to be served on real time basis. I need to deploy these application into the production using kubernetes. I also work on developing data pipeline which then later used by ML Models.
- > My roles in this team as a Software engineer. I need to interact with different data scientist to understand their ML model then design an application to deploy it into the production. my role requires from developing an applicatin to deploying it into the production.

**Bank Of America** June 2017 – Feb 2020

Senior Software Engineer, Python Developer

Mumbai. Maharashtra

- > Working on development project where we are trying to build One Trading Application for the all line of business, instead of multiple, which can save a lot of operational cost of managing multiple Trading **Applications**
- > My roles in this team as a python developer. I get involved in development, testing and deployment through Agile process. We use here Jira, Bit Bucket, and SVN tools to do the development.

Accenture Feb. 2016 – June 2017 Software Engineer Mumbai, Maharashtra

> Maintained a desktop application, which is used by MetLife client for displaying Illustration for their

> I was a software developer in this project. I was responsible here for requirement understanding, providing estimation, software development, testing, and deployment and build management via version control system.

#### **Tata Consultance Services**

June 2013 – Feb. 2016

System Engineer

Mumbai. Maharashtra

- > I had worked in TCS for NSE client for Trading system software.
- > In this project, I have worked as a software developer in C, C++, STL, Socket programming, multithreading, and SMFS database on Linux machine. I have good command over Linux command and shell scripting. I have acquainted knowledge of capital market trading system. I have successfully passed NSE capital market beginners module exam.